Register of the Atlantic Council of the United States Records, 1950-1986
Hoover Institution Archives
Atlantic Council of the United States records
1950-1986
82069
Hoover Institution Archives
373 manuscript boxes, 7 envelopes, 3 videotape cassettes, 2 motion picture film reels, 5 microfilm reels, 3 phonorecords, 12 phonotape reels (159.2 linear feet)
Correspondence, memoranda, reports, studies, minutes of meetings, conference proceedings, bulletins, financial records, and printed matter, relating to NATO, and American foreign, military and economic policy. Includes records of the Atlantic Institute, the Atlantic Treaty Association, the Committee on Atlantic Studies, and the Atlantic Congress of 1959.
Atlantic Council of the United States.
Access
Collection stored off site; a minimum of two days notice is required for use. Boxes may be requested through Stanford's online catalog at http://searchworks.stanford.edu/
The Hoover Institution Archives only allows access to copies of audiovisual items. To listen to sound recordings or to view videos or films during your visit, please contact the Archives at least two working days before your arrival. We will then advise you of the accessibility of the material you wish to see or hear. Please note that not all audiovisual material is immediately accessible.
Acquisition Information
Acquired by the Hoover Institution Archives in 1982.
Accruals
Materials may have been added to the collection since this finding aid was prepared. To determine if this has occurred, find the collection in Stanford University's online catalog at http://searchworks.stanford.edu/. Materials have been added to the collection if the number of boxes listed in the online catalog is larger than the number of boxes listed in this finding aid.
Historical Note:
The Atlantic Council of the United States was established in 1961 in Washington, D.C. It is a private American organization which encourages U.S. participation in the North Atlantic Treaty Organization and other international relations. The Council also works for the strengthening of U.S. private sector links in the fields of trade, finance, investment, sciences, technology, communications and education with the other North Atlantic countries.
The Council is a non-profit organization which has financial support from corporations, foundations, and individual businessmen, financiers, labor leaders and others. It maintains fraternal ties with similar organizations in other nations of the North Atlantic Treaty Organization.
The Atlantic Institute and the Atlantic Treaty Association are private international organizations which promote cooperation among the Atlantic countries. They research the forces at work in the Atlantic area, organize meetings, and prepare reports, studies and policy recommendations for influential administrators in their countries. The Boards of Governors, staff and financing come from various countries.
The Atlantic Council and the Atlantic Institute formed the Committee on Atlantic Studies in 1964. This committee consists of scholars from leading universities who advise the Boards of the Atlantic Council and the Atlantic Institute. The goal of the committee is to bring about a greater appreciation in American education of the economic, political, and cultural changes which are taking place in Western civilization.
Atlantic Congress (1959: London); Atlantic Institute for International Affairs.; Atlantic Treaty Association.; Committee on Atlantic Studies; North Atlantic Treaty Organization.; Europe; Europe--Foreign relations--United States.; Europe--Relations--United States; Moving-pictures.; Phonorecords.; Phonotapes.; United States--Commerce.; United States--Foreign relations--1945-1989.; United States--Foreign relations--Europe.; United States--Foreign relations.; United States--Military policy.; United States--Relations--Europe; Video tapes.
- CHRONOLOGICAL FILE, 1961-1980. (Box 1-3)
  Scope and Contents note
  Incoming and outgoing correspon-dence, memoranda, studies, reports, essays, printed matter and other materials arranged chronologically.
- CORRESPONDENCE, 1959-1981. (Box 3-35)
  Correspondence arranged alphabeti-cally by last name of correspondent or name of institution.
- SUBJECT FILE, 1950-1985. (Box 35-297)
  Correspondence, reports, memoranda, studies, essays, financial records, minutes of meetings, clip-pings, printed matter, and other materials pertaining to the operations of the Atlantic Council and its various sub-organi-zations.
- ATLANTIC CONGRESS, LONDON, JUNE 1959. (Box 297-312)
  Correspondence, reports, studies, minutes of meetings, press releases, clippings, and printed matter relating to the Atlantic Congress in London, June 1959.
- ATLANTIC INSTITUTE, 1959-1978. (Box 312-344)
  Correspondence, reports, minutes of meetings, financial records, lists, studies, printed matter, and clippings, relating to the operations of the Atlantic Institute.
- ATLANTIC TREATY ASSOCIATION, 1965-1983. (Box 344-364)
  Correspondence, reports, memoranda, minutes of meetings, financial records, studies, printed matter, and lists, relating to the operations of the Atlantic Treaty Association.
- COMMITTEE ON ATLANTIC STUDIES, 1964-1972. (Box 364-373)
  Correspondence, reports, minutes of meetings, financial records, lists, studies, printed matter, and clippings, relating to the operations of the Committee on Atlantic Studies.
- PHONORECORDS
- PHONOTAPES and VIDEOTAPES
- PHOTOGRAPHS.
  See photo card catalogue for description.
- MICROFILMS
- MOTION PICTURE FILMS
- CHRONOLOGICAL FILE, 1961-1980
  - 1961 (1, Folder 1)
  - 1962 (Folder 2)
  - 1964-65 (Folder 3)
  - 1965-67 (Folder 4)
  - 1967 (Folder 5)
  - 1967-68 (Folder 6)
  - 1968 (Folder 7)
  - 1968-1972 (Folder 8)
  - 1969 (Folder 9)
  - 1970 (Folder 10)
  - 1971 (Folder 11-12)
  - 1971-72 (2, Folder 1)
  - 1972 (Folder 2-4)
  - 1972-73 (Folder 5)
  - 1973 (Folder 6-7)
  - 1973-74 (Folder 8)
  - 1974 (Folder 9)
  - 1974 (3, Folder 1-2)
  - 1975 (Folder 3)
  - 1977 (Folder 4)
  - 1978 (Folder 5)
  - 1980 (Folder 6)
- CORRESPONDENCE, 1959-1981
  - Chronological
    - 1959-1960 (3, Folder 7)
    - 1962-63 (Folder 8)
    - 1964
      - January-March (Folder 9)
      - February (Folder 10)
      - March (Folder 11)
      - March (4, Folder 1)
      - April (Folder 2)
      - April-May (Folder 3)
      - May (Folder 4)
      - June (Folder 5-6)
      - June-July (5, Folder 1)
      - July (Folder 2)
      - August (Folder 3)
      - August-September (Folder 4)
      - September (Folder 5)
      - October (Folder 6-7)
      - October-November (6, Folder 1)
      - December (Folder 2)
    - 1965
      - January (Folder 3)
      - February (Folder 4)
      - March (Folder 5)
      - April (Folder 6)
      - May (Folder 7)
      - June (Folder 8)
      - July-August (7, Folder 1)
      - September-October (Folder 2)
      - November-December (Folder 3)
    - 1966 January-December (Folder 4-5)
    - 1967
      - July (Folder 6)
      - August (Folder 7)
      - September (Folder 8)
      - October (Folder 9)
      - November (Folder 10)
      - December (8, Folder 1)
    - 1967-69
    - 1968 (Folder 2)
      - January (Folder 3)
      - February (Folder 4)
      - March (Folder 5)
      - April (Folder 6)
      - May (Folder 7)
      - June-July (Folder 8)
      - August-September (Folder 9)
      - October (9, Folder 1)
      - November-December (Folder 2)
    - 1969
      - January-March (Folder 3)
      - April-June (Folder 4)
      - July-August (Folder 5)
      - September (Folder 6)
      - October (Folder 7)
      - November-December (Folder 8)
      - various months (Folder 9-10)
    - 1970
      - January-February (10, Folder 1)
      - March (Folder 2)
      - March-December (Folder 3)
      - April (Folder 4)
      - June (Folder 5)
      - July-August (Folder 6)
      - September (Folder 7)
      - October (Folder 8)
      - November (Folder 9)
      - December (Folder 10)
      - various months (11, Folder 1)
    - 1970-71 (Folder 2)
    - 1971
      - January-May (Folder 3)
      - June-August (Folder 5)
      - September-December (Folder 6)
      - various months (Folder 7)
    - 1971-72 (Folder 8)
    - 1972
      - January-March (12, Folder 1)
      - April-June (Folder 2)
      - July-September (Folder 3)
      - October-December (Folder 4)
      - various months (Folder 5)
    - 1973
      - January-April (Folder 6)
      - May-August (Folder 7)
      - September-December (Folder 8)
    - 1974
      - January-March (13, Folder 1)
      - April-June (Folder 2)
      - July-August (Folder 3)
      - September-October (Folder 4)
      - November-December (Folder 5)
    - 1975
      - January-February (Folder 6)
      - January-June (Folder 6A)
      - March-April (Folder 7)
      - May (Folder 8)
      - June-July (14, Folder 1)
      - August-September (Folder 2)
    - 1980 (Folder 3)
    - 1980-81 (Folder 4)
  - Alphabetical
    - A
      - 1962-68 (Folder 5)
      - 1965-67 (Folder 6)
    - Academy of Sciences, 1961-67 (Folder 7)
    - Acheson, David C., 1976 (Folder 8)
    - Acheson, Dean, 1962-69
    - Achilles, Marion, 1963 (Folder 10)
    - Agger, Donald, 1962-63 (Folder 11)
    - Alabama, University of (McLin, Jon), 1966-67 (Folder 12)
    - Allen, George V., 1964 (Folder 13)
    - American Bankers Association, 1965-67 (Folder 14)
    - American Colleges in Istanbul, 1963-65 (15, Folder 1)
    - American Good Government Society, 1966 (Folder 2)
    - American Nuclear Society, 1978-79 (Folder 3)
    - American Security Council, 1976-78 (Folder 4)
    - American Trade Press Clippings Bureau, 1965 (Folder 5)
    - American University, 1963-65 (Folder 6)
    - Anderson, Dillon, 1967-1970 (Folder 7)
    - Anderson, Robert B., 1963 (Folder 8)
    - Association Atlantique Belge, 1964-67 (Folder 9)
    - Association for Western Cooperation (Iceland), 1966-67 (Folder 10)
    - Association Francaise Pour la Communaute Atlantique, 1964-69 (Folder 11)
    - Association of International Relations Clubs, 1962 (Folder 12)
    - Atlantic College (U.K.), 1964-66 (Folder 13)
    - Atlantic Council of Canada, 1963-68 (Folder 14)
    - Atlantische Commissie (Netherlands), 1962-69 (Folder 15)
    - Altschul, Frank, 1962-63 (Folder 16)
    - Auburn University (Ivey, Oliver), 1963-64 (Folder 17)
    - B
      - 1963-68 (16, Folder 1-2)
      - 1964 (Folder 3)
      - 1965-67 (Folder 4)
    - Baird, John A., 1976 (Folder 5)
    - Barnaby, Frank, 1976-77 (Folder 6)
    - Barrett, Edward W., 1962-63 (Folder 7)
    - Barton-Gillet Company, 1962 (Folder 8)
    - Batt, William, 1962-63 (Folder 9)
    - Berding, Andrew, 1968 (Folder 10)
    - Beveridge, Ewart, 1965 (Folder 11)
    - Birgi, Nuri, 1976 (Folder 12)
    - Black, Eugene, 1962-63 (Folder 13)
    - Blackwelder, Justin, 1962-69 (Folder 14)
    - Blaustein, Jacob, 1965-1970 (Folder 15)
    - Boston Regional Conference for NATO, 1960-64 (Folder 16)
    - Brannigan, Patrick Jr., 1968 (Folder 17)
    - British Atlantic Committee
      - 1963-68 (Folder 18)
      - 1973 (Folder 19)
    - British Embassy, Washington, D.C., 1962-63 (Folder 20)
    - Brodschi, George, 1968-69 (17, Folder 1)
    - Brooklyn College, 1964-65 (Folder 2)
    - Brown University, 1964 (Folder 3)
    - Burgess, W. Randolph, 1962-67 (Folder 4)
    - Burke, S. M., 1962 (Folder 5)
    - Burlingham, Lloyd, 1963 (Folder 6)
    - Bushner, Rolland, 1964 (Folder 7)
    - C
      - 1962-64 (Folder 8)
      - 1963-68 (Folder 9-11)
      - 1965-67 (Folder 12)
    - California, University of (Berkeley), 1963-67 (Folder 13)
    - California, University of (Los Angeles), 1963-65 (Folder 14)
    - Canadian-American Committee, 1965 (Folder 15)
    - Capital City Press, 1967-68 (Folder 16)
    - Careers Incorporated, 1969 (18, Folder 1)
    - Carleton College (Lang, Reginald), 1963-65 (Folder 2)
    - Carnegie Corporation, 1965-67 (Folder 3)
    - Catholic University, 1965 (Folder 4)
    - Catudal, Marc, 1978-79 (Folder 5-8)
    - Center for Information on America, 1963-64 (Folder 9)
    - Center for Strategic and International Studies, 1976 (Folder 10)
    - Centre d'Information et de Documentation Atlantique, 1965 (Folder 11)
    - Century Association, 1965 (Folder 12)
    - Cherry, Bernard H., 1975-79 (Folder 13)
    - Childs, Marquis, 1965 (Folder 14)
    - Cincinnati Council on World Affairs, 1975 (Folder 15)
    - Citizens Conference on State Legislatures, 1969 (Folder 16)
    - Clay, Lucius D., 1964-67 (Folder 17)
    - Cleveland, Harlan, 1970 (19, Folder 1)
    - Cleveland, Harlan Van, 1963 (Folder 2)
    - Cleveland World Affairs Council, 1967 (Folder 3)
    - Clayton, William L., l962-64 (Folder 4)
    - Colgate University, 1963-65 (Folder 5)
    - Columbia University
      - 1963-66 (Folder 6)
      - (Teachers' College), 1964-65 (Folder 7)
    - Combs, T. Neal, 1970 (Folder 8)
    - Comissao Portuguesa do Atlantico, 1964-69 (Folder 9)
    - Comitato Italiano Atlantico, 1965-67 (Folder 10)
    - Comite Atlantique du Luxembourg, 1967 (Folder 11)
    - Committee on Educational Interchange Policy, 1962 (Folder 12)
    - Conant, James B., 1962-63 (Folder 13)
    - Conference Board, 1975 (Folder 14)
    - Congratulatory letters, 1964 (Folder 15)
    - Corbett, David E., 1966-67 (Folder 16)
    - Cosmos Club, 1963-65 (Folder 17)
    - Council on Foreign Relations
      - 1961-66 (Folder 18)
      - 1968-1975 (Folder 19)
      - 1969 (Folder 20)
    - D
      - 1962-64 (Folder 21)
      - 1962-68 (20, Folder 1)
      - 1964-67 (Folder 2)
    - Dainelli, Luca, 1974 (Folder 3)
    - Danforth Foundation, 1972 (Folder 4)
    - Danish Atlantic Association, 1962-1970 (Folder 5)
    - Dartmouth College, 1963-66 (Folder 6)
    - Davies, Jack L., 1968 (Folder 7)
    - Declaration of Atlantic Unity (Moore, Walden), 1963-67 (Folder 8)
    - De Guingand, Sir Francis, 1962 (Folder 9)
    - De Madre, Jean, 1975-76 (Folder 10)
    - Dennison, Robert L., 1965-67 (Folder 11)
    - Denver, University of, 1963-66 (Folder 12)
    - Deshormes, Philippe, 1969-1970 (Folder 13)
    - Dickeman, Raymond L., 1976-78 (Folder 14)
    - Dilworth, J. Richardson, 1963 (Folder 15)
    - Douglas, Lewis, 1966-1970 (Folder 16)
    - Draper, William H., 1965-67 (Folder 17)
    - Driscoll, George, 1975-77 (Folder 18)
    - E
      - 1962-64 (21, Folder 1)
      - 1963-68 (Folder 2)
    - Eastman Kodak Company, 1971-72 (Folder 3)
    - Elkus, Richard J., 1965 (Folder 4)
    - Emanuelli, Pierre, 1972 (Folder 5)
    - European University (Italy), 1964 (Folder 6)
    - F
      - 1963-68 (Folder 7)
      - 1964 (Folder 8)
      - 1965-67 (Folder 9)
    - Finletter, Thomas K., 1966-1970 (Folder 10)
    - Fletcher School of Law and Diplomacy (Tufts University), 1963-66 (Folder 11)
    - Florida Atlantic University, 1964-67 (Folder 12)
    - Flynt, Ralph C., 1965-69 (Folder 13)
    - Ford, Gerald R., 1974 (Folder 14)
    - Foreign Policy Research Institute (Kahn, Walter F.), 1975 (Folder 15)
    - Fosdick, Dorothy, 1968 (Folder 16)
    - Franklin, George S., 1966-1974 (Folder 17)
    - Free University of Brussels (Angelo, Homer), 1964-65 (Folder 18)
    - Freiburg University, 1963-65 (Folder 19)
    - Fulbright, J. W., 1966 (Folder 20)
    - G
      - 1962-64 (Folder 21)
      - 1963-68 (22, Folder 1)
      - 1964-65 (Folder 2)
      - 1965 (Folder 3)
      - 1965-67 (Folder 4)
    - Garwin, Richard L., 1977-78 (Folder 5)
    - Gasteyger, Curt, 1976-78 (Folder 6)
    - Geiger, Theodore, 1965-1970 (Folder 7)
    - General Federation of Women's Clubs, 1969-1970 (Folder 8)
    - General Media Associates, 1964-65 (Folder 9)
    - George Washington University, 1963-67 (Folder 10)
    - German Military Representative to MC, NATO, 1962 (Folder 11)
    - Gerry, Harvey S., 1967 (Folder 12)
    - Gilpatrick, Roswell L., 1967 (Folder 13)
    - Goodman, Elliot R., 1974-76 (Folder 14)
    - Gopperl, Michael, 1975-79 (Folder 15)
    - Governmental Affairs Institute, 1966 (Folder 16)
    - Gruenther, Alfred, 1968 (Folder 17)
    - H
      - 1962-64 (Folder 18)
      - 1964-66 (Folder 19)
      - 1965-68 (23, Folder 1)
    - Harrison, Stanley, 1968 (Folder 2)
    - Hartley, Livingston, 1962-64 (Folder 3)
    - Harvard Center for International Affairs, 1977 (Folder 4)
    - Harvard University
      - 1963-65 (Folder 5)
      - 1968 (Folder 6)
    - Hawaii, University of (East-West Center), 1965 (Folder 7)
    - Heiskell, Andrew, 1965 (Folder 8)
    - Hellenic Atlantic Treaty Association, 1962-67 (Folder 9)
    - Henry, Gerald B., 1965-67 (Folder 10)
    - Herod, William Rogers, 1965-66 (Folder 11)
    - Hettinger, A. J., 1971 (Folder 12)
    - Hickerson, John D.
      - 1963-64 (Folder 13)
      - 1972-75 (Folder 14)
    - Hoover Institution, 1963-64 (Folder 15)
    - Houston, University of, 1964-67 (Folder 16)
    - Hovey, Allan, Jr., 1962-64 (Folder 17)
    - Howard University, 1963-65 (Folder 18)
    - Hudson Institute, 1964-65 (Folder 19)
    - Hughes, John C., 1965-67 (Folder 20)
    - Humphrey, Hubert H., 1969 (Folder 21)
    - I
      - 1962-67 (Folder 22)
      - 1963-64 (Folder 23)
    - Imai, Ryukichi, 1975-78 (Folder 24)
    - Indiana University, 1964-65 (Folder 25)
    - Indiana University, West European Studies Program, 1964-66 (24, Folder 1)
    - Institut Canadien des Affaires Publiques, 1962 (Folder 2)
    - Institut des Hautes Etudes Internationales (Geneva), 1965 (Folder 3)
    - Internal Revenue Service, 1971-74 (Folder 4)
    - International Monetary Fund, 1965-66 (Folder 5)
    - International Relations Club, 1966 (Folder 6)
    - International University (Nice), 1964-67 (Folder 7)
    - Iowa Wesleyan University, 1966-67 (Folder 8)
    - Irish Council of the European Movement, 1963 (Folder 9)
    - J, 1962-67 (Folder 11)
    - Jackson, Cecil, 1968 (Folder 12)
    - Jacoby, Henry D., 1975 (Folder 13)
    - Javits, Jacob, 1968 (Folder 14)
    - Johns Hopkins University, Bologna Center
      - 1963-65 (Folder 15)
      - 1966-67 (Folder 16)
    - Johnson, Lyndon B., 1969 (Folder 17)
    - Jordan, Robert, 1973-74 (Folder 18)
    - Joseph, Franz M., 1965-69 (Folder 19)
    - K
      - 1963-65 (Folder 20)
      - 1963-67 (25, Folder 1)
    - Kaiser, Karl, 1964 (Folder 2)
    - Kampelman, Max M., 1965-1970 (Folder 3)
    - Kansas, University of, 1965 (Folder 4)
    - Keagy, W. Robert, 1975-78 (Folder 5)
    - Kennedy, Edward M., 1968 (Folder 6)
    - Kennedy, John F., letters of condolence, November 1963 (Folder 7)
    - Kennedy, John F., Institute (Netherlands), 1966 (Folder 8)
    - Kleiman, Robert, 1975 (Folder 9)
    - Krauthoff, Louis C., 1965 (Folder 10)
    - L
      - 1962-64 (Folder 11)
      - 1963-68 (Folder 12)
      - 1964-67 (Folder 13)
    - Lafayette College, 1964-65 (Folder 14)
    - Leddy, John M., 1978 (Folder 15)
    - Lilienthal, David E., 1975-76 (Folder 16)
    - Lilly Endowment, Inc., 1976 (Folder 17)
    - Lodge, Henry Cabot, 1962-66 (Folder 18)
    - Loudon, J. H., 1971 (Folder 19)
    - Louisiana State University, 1965-67 (Folder 20)
    - M
      - 1962-64 (26, Folder 1)
      - 1963-67 (Folder 2)
      - 1965-67 (Folder 3)
    - Mc, 1965, 1967 (Folder 4)
    - McDonnell, James S., 1969 (Folder 5)
    - McElroy, Neil, 1967 (Folder 6)
    - Mahias, M. Pierre, 1964 (Folder 7)
    - Malmgren, Harald, 1970-77 (Folder 8)
    - Marshall Research Foundation, 1975-76 (Folder 9)
    - Massachusetts, University of, 1964-65 (Folder 10)
    - Massachusetts Institute of Technology, 1963-64 (Folder 11)
    - Meek, Samuel, 1971-77 (Folder 12)
    - Mercer University, 1963-64 (Folder 13)
    - Merchant, Livingston T.
      - 1969 (Folder 14)
      - 1972 (Folder 15)
    - Michigan, University of, 1964-66 (Folder 16)
    - Miller, R. Eric, 1975-77 (Folder 17)
    - Minnesota, University of, 1963-65 (Folder 18)
    - Moore, Ben, 1965-67 (27, Folder 1)
    - Moore, Hugh
      - 1962-63 (Folder 2)
      - 1965-1970 (Folder 3)
    - Moore, Walden, 1961-64 (Folder 4)
    - Moorhead State College, 1964-65 (Folder 5)
    - Mosely, Philip, 1963 (Folder 6)
    - Mount Holyoke College
      - 1963 (Folder 7)
      - 1975-79 (Folder 8)
    - Munk, Frank, 1963-64 (Folder 9)
    - Muntzing, L. Manning, 1975-78 (Folder 10)
    - N
      - 1962-64 (Folder 11)
      - 1962-68 (Folder 12-14)
      - 1963-66 (Folder 15)
      - 1965-67 (Folder 16)
    - National Association of Secondary School Principals, 1961-68 (28, Folder 1)
    - National Grange, 1963 (Folder 2)
    - National Planning Association, 1967 (Folder 3)
    - National Press Club, 1972 (Folder 4)
    - National Strategy Information Center, 1967 (Folder 5)
    - Nef, John U., 1966 (Folder 6)
    - New York City Hall, 1968 (Folder 7)
    - New York State Bankers Association, 1965 (Folder 8)
    - Nixon, Richard M.
      - 1968 (Folder 9)
      - 1973-74 (Folder 10)
    - Norstad, Lauris, 1963-64 (Folder 11)
    - North Atlantic Treaty Organization (NATO), 1968 (Folder 12)
    - Norwegian Atlantic Committee, 1967 (Folder 13)
    - Notre Dame, University of, 1963-65 (Folder 14)
    - Nuclear Assurance Corporation, 1976-77 (Folder 15)
    - O, 1963-67 (Folder 16)
    - Office of Economic Opportunity, 1968 (Folder 17)
    - Ohio State University, 1963-67 (Folder 18)
    - Oliver, Spencer, 1968 (Folder 19)
    - Oregon, University of, 1965 (Folder 20)
    - Orgill, Edmund, 1965-1970 (Folder 21)
    - Owen, Henry, 1968-69 (Folder 22)
    - P
      - 1962-68 (Folder 23)
      - 1963-68 (Folder 24-25)
      - 1965 (Folder 26)
    - Pace, Frank, 1962-66 (Folder 27)
    - Palfrey, John, 1975-79 (29, Folder 1)
    - Parker, Daniel, 1967-69 (Folder 2)
    - Paterson State College, 1964-65 (Folder 3)
    - Peccei, Aurelio, 1969-1970 (Folder 4)
    - Penfield, James K., 1965 (Folder 5)
    - Pennsylvania, University of, 1964-67 (Folder 6)
    - Pennsylvania State University, 1967 (Folder 7)
    - Petersen, James K., 1964 (Folder 8)
    - Phleger, Herman, 1968 (Folder 9)
    - Pick, Otto, 1972-78 (Folder 10)
    - Pierre, Andrew, 1969 (Folder 11)
    - Pittsburgh, University of, 1963-66 (Folder 12)
    - Planned Parenthood-World Population, 1964-69 (Folder 13)
    - Population Crisis Committee, 1975-76 (Folder 14)
    - Poullier, Jean Pierre, 1970 (Folder 15)
    - Princeton University, 1963-67 (Folder 16)
    - Pryor, Donald J., 1963 (Folder 17)
    - Purdue University, 1964-65 (Folder 18)
    - Quambusch, Liesel, 1970 (Folder 19)
    - Queens College (New York), 1964 (Folder 20)
    - R
      - 1962-64 (Folder 21)
      - 1963-67 (Folder 22)
      - 1965-67 (Folder 23)
    - Rasmussen, Norman C., 1975 (Folder 24)
    - Regan, Ben, 1962-67 (Folder 25)
    - Reid, Escott, 1980 (30, Folder 1)
    - Republican National Committee, 1978 (Folder 2)
    - Rice University, 1963-64 (Folder 3)
    - Ridgway, M. B., 1965 (Folder 4)
    - Rockefeller, Nelson, 1971 (Folder 5)
    - Rolfe, S. E., 1969 (Folder 6)
    - Roper, Elmo, 1963-1970 (Folder 7)
    - Rosenfeld, Stephen, 1968 (Folder 8)
    - Ross, Michael, 1962-63 (Folder 9)
    - Rostow, Eugene V., 1962-1973 (Folder 10)
    - Rostow, W. W., 1968 (Folder 11)
    - Rotary International, 1963-64 (Folder 12)
    - S
      - 1962-65 (Folder 13)
      - 1963-68 (Folder 14-15)
      - 1964-66 (Folder 16)
      - 1965-66 (Folder 17)
      - 1966-67 (31, Folder 1)
    - Saint John's Abbey and University, 1963-64 (Folder 2)
    - San Francisco State College, 1964-65 (Folder 3)
    - Scaife Family Charitable Trusts, 1976 (Folder 4)
    - Schelling, Thomas C., 1976 (Folder 5)
    - Scherman, Harry, 1965-69 (Folder 6)
    - Schmidt, Adolph W.
      - 1962 (Folder 7)
      - 1963-64 (Folder 8)
      - 1969-1979 (Folder 9)
      - 1973-74 (Folder 10)
      - 1974-76 (Folder 11)
    - Senn, Edouard, 1966 (Folder 12)
    - Servan-Schreiber, Jean Jacques, 1967-68 (Folder 13)
    - Simon, William E., 1976 (Folder 14)
    - Sims, Harold, 1968 (Folder 15)
    - Smith College (Mass.), 1964-65 (Folder 16)
    - Soberick, Thomas, 1969 (Folder 17)